Guide to the George W. Perkins papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
George W. Perkins Papers,
1895-1990
[Bulk Dates: 1909-1960].
Perkins, George W. (George Walbridge), 1862-1920.
25 linear ft. (55 boxes: 51 document boxes, 2 record cartons, 1 flat box, 1 slide box)
Columbia University. Rare Book and Manuscript Library New York, NY. 10027
MS#1491
4079209
This collection contains the papers of George W. Perkins, Jr., a diplomat who served as Assistant Secretary of State for European Affairs and as United States Permanent Representative to NATO. The bulk of the papers relates to his work for NATO and for the Palisades Interstate Park Commission, which he chaired. There are also documents pertaining to his service in the U.S. Army during World War I and World War II. Most of the material consists of correspondence and photographs.
Biographical Note
George W. Perkins, Jr. (1895-1960) was a diplomat who served as Assistant Secretary of State for European Affairs under Dean Acheson, from 1949 to 1953, and as the US Permanent Representative to NATO, with rank of Ambassador, from 1955 to 1957.
Perkins was born in 1895 to Evelina Ball Perkins and George W. Perkins. His father was a financier, member of J.P. Morgan & Co. and one of the founders of Theodore Roosevelt's Progressive Party. He was also president of the Palisades Interstate Park Commission from its creation in 1900 to 1920. George W. Perkins, Jr. pursued his undergraduate studies from 1913 to 1917 at Princeton University, and in 1921 received an MA from Columbia. During World War I, from 1917 to 1919, he served as a Lieutenant in the 1st Division of the US Army. While he was fighting in France in 1918, his wife, Katherine Trowbridge, whom he had married in 1917, died. In 1921 he married Linn Merck, daughter of George Merck, President of Merck and Co. The couple had three children.
From 1921 to 1922, Perkins was Executive Secretary to Postmaster General Will Hays, and then, from 1927 to 1948, he acted as Executive Vice President of Merck and Co. He took a leave of absence during World War II, from 1942 to 1945, while he was a Colonel working for the Chemical Warfare Service of the US Army. He was awarded the Legion of Merit for his service.
In 1949, President Harry Truman appointed Perkins, a Republican, to the post of Assistant Secretary of State for European Affairs. In the four years he held this position, he advocated for a more open attitude toward Spain and helped to win financial aid for Yugoslavia from Congress, arguing that it would be a way of deterring the Soviet Union. President Dwight Eisenhower appointed him United States Permanent Representative on the Council of NATO in 1955, five years after Perkins had served as the US representative in the formation of NATO. In 1957 he was succeeded by W. Randolph Burgess.
In his last years, Perkins was very devoted to the Palisades Park Interstate Commission, of which he had been a member since 1922. He became President in 1945 and served for 15 years. He died in 1960.
Scope and Content
The collection contains documents and photographs of George W. Perkins, Jr. Subject files include mostly official correspondence regarding organizations such as NATO, the Palisades Interstate Park Commissions, and Merck and Company. The bulk of these subject files were created by George W. Perkins, Jr. After his death, several folders with condolences and obituaries were added by his family. Also included are his documents from World War I and World War II: manuals, maps, correspondence, and photographs. His personal documents constitute a separate series, which includes correspondence with family and his two wives, papers from his school years and travel diaries. The papers also contain invitations, menus, and itineraries that illustrate his social life as a diplomat. Financial files include stocks and bonds as well as correspondence, clippings, and official documents regarding the bankruptcy of Knauth, Nachod and Kuhne. There is also a large amount of photographs and photo albums that include family portraits and photographs from travels.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged in seven series:
Series I. Subject Files Arranged by George W. Perkins, Jr., 1909-1985
Series II. Personal Documents, 1910-1960
Series III. Social Affairs, 1936-1957
Series IV. Financial Files, 1922-1937
Series V. Printed Material, 1909-1990
Series VI. Photographs, 1895-1970
Series VII. Other Media, 1940-1961.
Subjects
North Atlantic Treaty Organization.; North Atlantic Treaty Organization--Officials and employees.; North Atlantic Treaty Organization--United States.; Palisades Interstate Park Commission.; Perkins, George W. (George Walbridge), 1862-1920.; Palisades Interstate Park.; United States--Politics and government--20th century.; Steel industry and trade--United States.; Banks and banking--United States--History.; Chemical warfare--United States.; Insurance companies--United States.; Life insurance--History.; Agricultural machinery industry.; Industries--United States.; World War, 1914-1918.; World War, 1939-1945.; Industrialists.; Executives.; Capitalists and financiers.
Access Restrictions
This collection is located off-site. You will need to request this material at least twenty-four (24) hours in advance to use the collection in the Rare Book and Manuscript Library reading room. Box 55, which contains glass plate negatives, is located onsite.
This collection has no restrictions.
Acquisition
02/05/1960 M-60-02-05 Freeman, Mrs. Edward W. and George W. Perkins, Jr. Gift
- Series I: Subject Files Arranged by George W. Perkins, Jr., 1909-1985
  Most of the papers in this series were arranged by George W. Perkins, Jr.; several folders contain letters received by his family after his death. The labels chosen by Perkins were retained, excepting those in brackets within the finding aid. The series consists mostly of correspondence from the 1940s and 1950s, when Perkins was a US diplomat. Also included are his documents pertaining to the Palisades Interstate Park Commission: correspondence, data for developing projects, and speeches. Of particular interests are folders with papers from World War I, when Perkins served as Lieutenant, and World War II, when he worked for the Chemical Warfare Service as a Colonel. Contained here are handbooks and maps from training sessions held during World War I, as well as maps, folders with memos on chemical warfare, and reports on travels to several countries, especially India, during World War II.
  - [General], 1920s-1959, (6 Folders) (Box 1, Folder 1 to 6)
  - Acheson, Dean-- Truman Library, 1953-1956 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - American Council on NATO
    - [General], 1958-1959, (3 Folders) (Box 1, Folder 8 to 10)
    - [Correspondence--Outgoing], 1953-1955 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Fund Raising, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - International Conferences, 1952-1955 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - International Conferences, 1954-1955 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Ancestry Data, circa 1930s (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Assistant Secretary of State Matters, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Atlantic Congress
    - Atlantic Council of the U.S., 1959 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Europe, 1959, (2 Folders) (Box 2, Folder 5 to 6)
  - Ball, Flamen and Susan, David, 1947-1974 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Barbizon Conference, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Bonbright, James C. H., 1953-1958 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - BR, 1922-1959 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - BU, 1922-1958 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Burgess, W. Randolph--NATO, 1949-1959 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - C, 1920-1957 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Career Data, 1931-1960, (2 Folders) (Box 3, Folder 1 to 2)
  - Childhood, 1899-1910 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Condolence--A-Z, 1960, (6 Folders) (Box 3, Folder 4 to 9)
  - Correspondence
    - A-Z, 1917-1922 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - A-C, 1953-1958, (2 Folders) (Box 4, Folder 2 to 3)
    - A-Z, 1959, (4 Folders) (Box 4, Folder 4 to 7)
    - Linn Merck Perkins and George W. Perkins Jr--Paris, 1953-1958 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Council on Foreign Relations Inc., 1957-1966 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Cutting Arboretum, 1936-1958 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - De Bilderberg Conference, 1954-1957, (3 Folders) (Box 5, Folder 1 to 3)
  - Economic Cooperation Administration (ECA)
    - [General], 1948-1949, (2 Folders) (Box 5, Folder 4 to 5)
    - Travel Orders and Salary Information, 1948-1949 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Edgar, James A.--Personal and Investments, 1949-1972 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Eulogies, 1960 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - George W. Perkins, Jr., 1895-1960 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Glyndor Fire, circa 1926 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Haldane Commencement, undated (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Harriman, W. Averell, 1949-1970 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Harriman, E. Roland, 1923-1959 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - He, 1919-1970 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Hempstead, Mrs. Lucie G. (Baysis)--Mrs. Alan, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Henry Hudson Memorial, 1920-1934 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Highlands Country Club, 1925-1968 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Hill School
    - [General], 1911-1913 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - [Correspondence--Alumni--Outgoing], 1953-1955 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Manuscripts, 1911-1913 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Historic Georgetown Inc., 1952-1986 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Ho, 1957 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Hoskins, Harold B., 1953-1977 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Hughes, John C.--NATO, 1954-1959 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Impersonation, 1925 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Information for Who’s Who, 1943-1956 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Javits, Jacob K., 1949-1959 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Lee, Ivy L.--Personal Data, 1920-1921 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Letters Received upon Resigning as Assistant Secretary of State, 1953 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Library of Congress, 1954 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Major, Randolph J., 1943-1955 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Marsh, Harold N., 1922-1929 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Martin, Dr. Alexander T., 1925-1968 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Mayer, Charles, 1960-1961 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Mayer, Louis, 1931-1932 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Mc, 1920-1960 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Memorabilia, 1924-1961 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Merchant, Livingston T., 1953-1959 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Merck, Albert W., 1953-1986 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Merck and Co
    - [General], 1928-1929, (2 Folders) (Box 7, Folder 11 to 12)
    - [General], 1958-1960 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Family Stockholders, 1957-1958 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Merck Family
    - [General], 1934-1947 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence, 1921-1987 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Miller, William, 1950-1953 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Miscellaneous, 1920s-1948 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Mo, 1945-1961 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Mu, 1920-1955 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO)
    - [General], 1953-1959, (5 Folders) (Box 8, Folder 1 to 5)
    - National Conference, 1953-1955 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Parliamentarians’ Conference, 1955 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Social, 1955-1957 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Travel, 1955-1958, (2 Folders) (Box 8, Folder 9 to 10)
  - North Atlantic Council--Appointment and Resignation, 1955-1958 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - NY/NJ Trail Conference--Rothschild, 1958 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - New York Life Insurance Co, 1921-1990, (2 Folders) (Box 48, Folder 4 to 5)
  - Nolting, Frederick E., Jr., 1957-1969 (Box 48, Folder 6)
  - Norstad, Lauris General, 1959-1968 (Box 48, Folder 7)
  - Official Entertainment, 1955-1956, (3 Folders) (Box 48, Folder 8 to 10)
  - Ogden, Alfred, 1954-1989 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Osborn, Frederick, 1954-1958 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Page, Mrs. Walter H., 1953-1958 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Paget, Humphrey, 1949-1957 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Palisades Interstate Park Commission (PIPC)
    - [General], 1920-1980, (7 Folders) (Box 9, Folder 5 to 11)
    - 99 Year Lease, 1958-1959 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - AK Morgan, 1955-1957 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Albright, Horace Marden--Assistant Secretary, 1953-1959 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Appointment to Commission, 1936-1956, (2 Folders) (Box 10, Folder 3 to 4)
    - Bear Mountain Inn, 1926-1935 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Burnett Property, 1954-1958 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Commemorative Booklets, 1962 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Commissioner Mrs. Linn Merck Perkins, 1960-1973 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Condemnation Proceedings, 1930-1938 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Contributions, 1950 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence--Ideas on Uses of Park, 1939-1945 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence, 1941, (2 Folders) (Box 10, Folder 12 to 13)
    - Correspondence, 1942-1952, (13 Folders) (Box 11, Folder 1 to 13)
    - Correspondence, 1952-1959, (7 Folders) (Box 12, Folder 1 to 7)
    - Correspondence, 1959-1963, (4 Folders) (Box 13, Folder 1 to 4)
    - Data from Ken Morgan--Parkway Battle, 1946 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Forrest Lands, 1957-1959, (2 Folders) (Box 13, Folder 6 to 7)
    - Land Grants, 1954 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Letters to Hikers--Thruway, 1954 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - NY/NJ Metropolitan Region
      - Correspondence, 1958 (Box 48, Folder 12)
      - Speeches by George W. Perkins, Jr., 1958 (Box 48, Folder 13)
    - Parkway Data by George W. Perkins, Jr., 1945 (Box 49, Folder 1)
    - Parkway Project, 1954 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Personal, 1943-1945 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - [Report,] 1909 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Rockland Lake and Dellwood, 1959 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Rockefeller Contributions for Fort Clinton and Montgomery Restoration, 1928 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Sealantic, 1954-1955 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Speeches, 1945 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Passport Data, 1926-1955, (2 Folders) (Box 14, Folder 8 to 9)
  - Past Invitations, 1951 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Personal Data, 1916-1922 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Personal Data, 1916-1922 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Personal--Assistant Secretary of State, Truman Letter, 1950s (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Pi, 1931-1979 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Pocket Diaries, 1949, 1954-1958, (2 Folders) (Box 15, Folder 4 to 5)
  - Population, 1959-1960 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Post Office Matters, 1922-1928 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Presbyterian Foundation, NY, 1951-1959 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Press Clippings, 1942-1957 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Princeton University
    - [General], 1913-1917 (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - [General], 1913-1917, (3 Folders) (Box 16, Folder 1 to 3)
    - Bonds, 1936 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Honorary Degree, 1957 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Institute for Advanced Study, 1953-1954 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Ro--Rosehill Cemetery, 1917-1922 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Robert College, 1957 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Roberts, Mrs. Eugene B. (Marie Bonne), 1949-1963 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Robinson, J. Beverley and Duncan S., 1946-1956 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Rockefeller, 1954-1991 (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Romanian Bonds
    - Government Claim, 1959 (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - Joint Holdings, 1924-1925 (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - Joint Holdings, 1926-1928 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Notes, 1925-1926 (Box 49, Folder 2)
  - Rosengarten, Adolph G., Jr., 1953-1959 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Rusk, Dean--President Rockefeller Foundation, 1953-1956 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - S--Sanchez, 1940 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Schenck & Van Haelen, 1940 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Sea Island--[Correspondence--Outgoing], 1952-1955 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Speeches, 1947, 1951-1959, (2 Folders) (Box 17, Folder 7 to 8)
  - Speeches--Paris, 1955, (2 Folders) (Box 17, Folder 9 to 10)
  - Speeches--Paris, 1956-1957 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - St, 1957-1959 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - State Department
    - [General], 1949-1953, (2 Folders) (Box 18, Folder 3 to 4)
    - Appointment--Letters of Congratulations, 1949 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Travel, 1949-1950 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Stearns, Charles, 1942-1956 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Stewart, Weir, 1957 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Suspension of Powers as Executive, 1942 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Sympathy Acknowledgments, 1960 (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Theodore Roosevelt Association, 1912-1933 (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Ti, 1953-1954 (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Travel, 1956-1957 (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - Tributes, 1960 (Box 49, Folder 3)
  - [Trip to London], 1952 (Box 49, Folder 4)
  - Trusts for Children, 1931 (Box 49, Folder 5)
  - U, 1958 (Box 49, Folder 6)
  - US Permanent Representative to North Atlantic Council--Letters of Congratulation, 1955, (2 Folders) (Box 19, Folder 1 to 2)
  - Veterans Administration, 1945-1960 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - W, 1955-1970 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Western Trip, 1959, (2 Folders) (Box 19, Folder 5 to 6)
  - [World War I]
    - Army, 1917-1919, (3 Folders) (Box 19, Folder 7 to 9)
    - Army, 1917-1919, (5 Folders) (Box 20, Folder 1 to 5)
    - Personal Data, 1916-1936, (2 Folders) (Box 20, Folder 6 to 7)
  - [World War II]
    - Air Corps Requirements Affecting Items to Be Produced by the Chemical Warfare Service, 1942 (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - Army, 1944-1948, (5 Folders) (Box 21, Folder 1 to 5)
    - Army--Citation--Legion of Merit, 1945 (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Army--Data for Passport, 1919-1947 (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - Army--[Travel], 1944-1945, (2 Folders) (Box 21, Folder 8 to 9)
    - Army--Washington, 1940s (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - Maps, 1940s (Box 51, Folder 1)
    - Report of Trip to India and Southwest Pacific Area, 1944 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Toxic Gas Production in Industry, 1942 (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - US War Department, 1942, (2 Folders) (Box 22, Folder 3 to 4)
  - XYZ, 1948-1973 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Young Men’s Christian Association (YMCA), 1911-1921 (Box 22, Folder 6)
- Series II: Personal Documents, 1910-1960
  The bulk of this series is correspondence with friends and family, particularly with his mother, Evelina Perkins, his sister Dorothy (Polly) Perkins, his first wife, Katherine Trowbridge, and his second wife, Linn Merck Perkins. There are also notes and handbooks from his school days, papers documenting his participation in the 1908 and 1912 Republican Conventions, and drafts of a biography of his father, George W. Perkins, which was later used by Trumbull White for a book that was never published. This series also includes travel diaries from 1910 to 1931, some of which describe trips that were also photographed. The photographs are included in Series VI.
  - Biography of George W. Perkins by George W. Perkins, Jr.
    - Draft with Notes, 1920s, (4 Folders) (Box 22, Folder 7 to 10)
    - Draft with Notes, 1920s, (4 Folders) (Box 23, Folder 1 to 4)
  - Biography of George W. Perkins by Trumbull White--Draft, 1940s, (3 Folders) (Box 23, Folder 5 to 7)
  - Biography of George W. Perkins--Notes, undated (Box 50, Folder 1)
  - Browning School, 1906-1912 (Box 50, Folder 2)
  - Certificates and Diplomas, 1915-1960, (3 Folders) (Box 54, Folder 1 to 3)
  - Clippings, 1919-1960 (Box 50, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence
    - Children, 1942 (Box 50, Folder 4)
    - Cuomo, Anthony, 1916-1917, (5 Folders) (Box 24, Folder 1 to 5)
    - Engagement to Linn Merck, 1921, (2 Folders) (Box 24, Folder 6 to 7)
    - Friends, 1912-1916, (2 Folders) (Box 24, Folder 8 to 9)
    - Friends, 1912-1916, (10 Folders) (Box 25, Folder 1 to 10)
    - Friends, 1912-1916, (4 Folders) (Box 26, Folder 1 to 4)
    - Papers of George W. Perkins, 1960 (Box 50, Folder 5)
    - Perkins, Dorothy (Polly), 1912-1916, (4 Folders) (Box 26, Folder 5 to 8)
    - Perkins, Dorothy (Polly), 1912-1916, (7 Folders) (Box 27, Folder 1 to 7)
    - Perkins, Dorothy (Polly), 1912-1916, (7 Folders) (Box 28, Folder 1 to 7)
    - Perkins, Evelina, 1912-1917, (7 Folders) (Box 29, Folder 1 to 7)
    - Perkins, Evelina, 1912-1917, (7 Folders) (Box 30, Folder 1 to 7)
    - Perkins, George W., Jr. to Linn Merck Perkins, 1920-1924, (2 Folders) (Box 50, Folder 6 to 7)
    - Perkins, George W., Jr. to Linn Merck Perkins, 1920-1924, (3 Folders) (Box 31, Folder 1 to 3)
    - Perkins, Linn Merck, 1919-1942, (4 Folders) (Box 31, Folder 4 to 7)
    - Perkins, Linn Merck, 1919-1942, (8 Folders) (Box 32, Folder 1 to 8)
    - Perkins, Linn Merck, 1919-1942, (2 Folders) (Box 33, Folder 1 to 2)
    - Trowbridge, Katherine, 1916-1918, (5 Folders) (Box 33, Folder 3 to 7)
    - Trowbridge, Katherine, 1916-1918, (5 Folders) (Box 34, Folder 1 to 5)
    - Princeton Summer Camp, 1916 (Box 34, Folder 6)
  - George W. Perkins, circa 1915 (Box 34, Folder 7)
  - Handwritten Notes, undated (Box 34, Folder 8)
  - Hill School
    - General, 1910-1911 (Box 34, Folder 9)
    - General, 1912-1913 (Box 35, Folder 1)
    - Scrapbook, 1910-1913 (Box 53, Folder 1)
  - House in Washington--Drawing, undated (Box 54, Folder 4)
  - New Testament, 1917 (Box 50, Folder 8)
  - Princeton University
    - General, 1913-1917 (Box 35, Folder 2)
    - Charter Club, 1917 (Box 35, Folder 3)
    - Class Day, 1916, (2 Folders) (Box 35, Folder 4 to 5)
    - Student Handbooks, 1912-1916 (Box 35, Folder 6)
  - Republican Convention
    - 1908 (Box 35, Folder 7)
    - 1912 (Box 35, Folder 8)
  - Travel Diary
    - Central and South America, 1922 (Box 35, Folder 9)
    - Gibraltar, Algiers, Palermo, Naples, Athens, Istanbul, Vienna, 1931 (Box 35, Folder 10)
    - Maine, 1910 (Box 36, Folder 1)
- Series III: Social Affairs, 1936-1957
  This series consists of ephemera related to the Perkins’s social life while he was working as an Assistant Secretary of State for European Affairs in Washington, DC from 1949 to 1953 and, later, as a US Permanent Representative to NATO in Paris, from 1955 to 1957. Included are invitations to official ceremonies and dinners, menus, itineraries, clippings as well as papers regarding official visits to countries such as Austria, Germany, and the UK.
  - General, 1950s (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - Calling Cards, undated (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - Ceremonies, 1951-1956, (2 Folders) (Box 36, Folder 4 to 5)
  - Clippings, 1936-1950s (Box 36, Folder 6)
  - Cruises, 1950-1951 (Box 36, Folder 7)
  - Date Books, 1950-1951, (2 Folders) (Box 36, Folder 8 to 9)
  - Entertainment--Paris, 1952-1957 (Box 36, Folder 10)
  - Inauguration Ceremonies, 1953 (Box 49, Folder 7)
  - Invitations, 1949-1957, (4 Folders) (Box 49, Folder 8 to 11)
  - Invitations, 1949-1957, (5 Folders) (Box 37, Folder 1 to 5)
  - Invitations, 1949-1957, (7 Folders) (Box 38, Folder 1 to 7)
  - Invitations, 1949-1957, (8 Folders) (Box 39, Folder 1 to 8)
  - Itineraries, 1950s (Box 39, Folder 9)
  - Menus, 1952-1957, (2 Folders) (Box 40, Folder 1 to 2)
  - Official Dinners, 1950-1957, (2 Folders) (Box 40, Folder 3 to 4)
  - Official Visits, 1951-1955 (Box 40, Folder 5)
  - The Social List of Washington, D.C., 1953 (Box 40, Folder 6)
  - Thank You Notes, 1950-1957 (Box 40, Folder 7)
  - Travel
    - Austria and Germany, 1952 (Box 40, Folder 8)
    - Berlin, 1957 (Box 40, Folder 9)
    - Berlin, 1957 (Box 41, Folder 1)
    - London, 1950 (Box 41, Folder 2)
- Series IV: Financial Files, 1922-1937
  Contained here are a variety of bonds and stocks from the 1920s and 1930s as well as correspondence about financial matters. The bulk of this series consist of documents pertaining to the bankruptcy of Knauth, Nachod and Kuhne, which include the Supreme Court decision on Charles S. Martin against William C. Peyton, George W. Perkins, Jr., Anne du Pont Peyton, Evelina B. Perkins, Dorothy Perkins Freeman and Edward W. Freeman.
  - Bonds and Stocks, 1922-1931 (Box 51, Folder 2)
  - Chase Bank--Correspondence, 1923-1924 (Box 51, Folder 3)
  - Interstate Fish Corporation, 1922-1925, (2 Folders) (Box 51, Folder 4 to 5)
  - Knauth, Nachod and Kuhne
    - Assets and Liabilities, 1923 (Box 51, Folder 3)
    - Bankruptcy, 1924, (3 Folders) (Box 51, Folder 6 to 8)
    - Clippings, 1923-1924 (Box 50, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, 1922-1925, (4 Folders) (Box 42, Folder 1 to 4)
    - Liquidation Agreement, 1924 (Box 42, Folder 5)
    - Statement of Cash in Hands of Trustee and Unliquidated Assets, August 31 1924 (Box 51, Folder 4)
    - Statement of Unliquidated Assets and Liabilities, July 31, 1925 (Box 50, Folder 10)